<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Infosec on Secret Chipmunk</title>
    <link>//localhost:1313/tags/infosec/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Infosec on Secret Chipmunk</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>(c) 2021 Ron Parker</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/tags/infosec/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Making Security Decisions Like a Boss</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/blog/2022/06/10/making-security-decisions-like-a-boss/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/blog/2022/06/10/making-security-decisions-like-a-boss/</guid>
      <description>How do we make good security decisions? aaaaaa&#xA;It has been a busy year. A lot of time was spent actually working with AWS and a good many of their offerings. So much time that the whole year flew by and I almost didn&amp;rsquo;t have the time to take the certification I had been working on for so long.&#xA;Another issue was that test centers were still not open in my area so the testing had to be proctored.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AWS Solution Architect Professional (SAP)</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/blog/2020/12/30/aws-solution-architect-professional-sap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/blog/2020/12/30/aws-solution-architect-professional-sap/</guid>
      <description>On Flying Time It has been a busy year. A lot of time was spent actually working with AWS and a good many of their offerings. So much time that the whole year flew by and I almost didn&amp;rsquo;t have the time to take the certification I had been working on for so long.&#xA;Another issue was that test centers were still not open in my area so the testing had to be proctored.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>AWS Certification</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/blog/2019/06/18/aws-certification/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/blog/2019/06/18/aws-certification/</guid>
      <description>Certification Path Amazon has several paths for certification that target different job roles. Having an architecture and a security background I decided to move towards the full AWS Solution Architect first then pursue a security specialty later on if it seemed valuable. The first place to start is an overview for the learning paths&#xA;After looking at the prerequisites my certification path looks like this:&#xA;Cloud Practitioner -&amp;gt; Solution Architect-Associate -&amp;gt; Solution architecture</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Capabilities All The Way Down</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/blog/2018/08/23/security-capabilities-all-the-way-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 12:45:30 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/blog/2018/08/23/security-capabilities-all-the-way-down/</guid>
      <description>All the Way Down We continue our series on using capabilities to our advantage in creating design and architecture. We will cover how we can model information security all the way down. This section, like the section on Cloud Capabilities, begins with the layout of those abilities.&#xA;We also have to remember that capabilities are the highest level or the highest description we will be using. The actual behaviors and implementations will be much more detailed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security BSides Chattanooga 2018</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/blog/2018/02/28/security-bsides-chattanooga-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2018 14:24:35 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/blog/2018/02/28/security-bsides-chattanooga-2018/</guid>
      <description>Security BSides You probably already know about Security BSides and how they came about. If not jump on over to BSides to get the scoop.&#xA;There are many BSides events around the Chattanooga area. We have them in Knoxville, Nashville, Asheville, Atlanta, and Huntsville just to name the ones that come to mind. Chattanooga is a growing tech community and has many large and small businesses that have security concerns.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Certified Cloud Security Professional Test</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/blog/2016/10/28/the-certified-cloud-security-professional-test/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Oct 2016 14:24:35 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/blog/2016/10/28/the-certified-cloud-security-professional-test/</guid>
      <description>First things first The most important point, for me anyway, is that I passed the test.&#xA;It was helpful for me to hear how other people passed their tests and how they obtained their certifications. I can&amp;rsquo;t guarantee that you will pass the test if you read this but hopefully you will pick up a couple of tips that may help you along the way.&#xA;What is the CCSP The (ISC)2 CCSP is a joint effort between the (ISC)2 and the Cloud Security Alliance.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Entitlements in a Multi-tenant World</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/blog/2016/09/18/entitlements-in-a-multi-tenant-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2016 12:21:29 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/blog/2016/09/18/entitlements-in-a-multi-tenant-world/</guid>
      <description>We are in a super-shared, and super-scaled world where rights are no longer concentrated in one place. Your rights and permissions are living everywhere in the neighborhood. They have left home.&#xA;These is the presentation I used for a basic talk on why it is important to understnad how entitlements work these day. It was meant for presenting but you may get somehting out of it.&#xA;Entitlements in a Multi-tenant World(PDF) Entitlements in a Multi-tenant World(PPTx) </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>B-Sides Nashville 2016 Presentation</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/blog/2016/04/17/b-sides-nashville-2016-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2016 11:24:54 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/blog/2016/04/17/b-sides-nashville-2016-presentation/</guid>
      <description>IAM Complicated: Why you need to know about Identity and Access Management&#xA;B-Sides Nashville 2016 was a great event. Here are the links for the presentation.&#xA;The IAM Complicated Recording thanks to Iron Geek.&#xA;IAM Complicated Presentation(PPTX)&#xA;IAM Complicated Presentation(PDF)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>B-Sides Nashville 2016</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/blog/2016/02/24/b-sides-nashville-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 11:24:54 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/blog/2016/02/24/b-sides-nashville-2016/</guid>
      <description>I have been given the opportunity to speak at B-Sides Nashville 2016. This year&amp;rsquo;s topic will be all about identity access and management.&#xA;IAM Complicated: Why you need to know about Identity and Access Management&#xA;Do you know where identities are born? How can you tell what an identify can and can&amp;rsquo;t do? What do you do when you realize your refrigerator has an identity of its own? If your IPS blocks your refrigerator you may lose access to your pizza.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OpenSDL Presentation</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/blog/2015/04/25/opensdl-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2015 15:00:45 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/blog/2015/04/25/opensdl-presentation/</guid>
      <description>Here is the condensed version of how to mix security into agile development.&#xA;Agile and Security. (PDF)&#xA;Concept Platform A basic framework for the concept has been built around a Wiki and the OpenSAMM. This framework should be good enough to grow the idea and determine if it will add security value. The current version is here:&#xA;Http://www.OpenSDL.com</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>B-Sides Nashville 2015</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/blog/2015/04/14/b-sides-nashville-2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 11:24:54 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/blog/2015/04/14/b-sides-nashville-2015/</guid>
      <description>I got the opportunity to be at B-Sides in Nashville over the weekend. It was a great opportunity to mingle and meet people who had an interest in information security. One of the best parts was a great mix of old professionals and quite a few new people who were interesting in seeing what security is all about. It was a good time and I appreciate all the effort it took to make it happen.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open Security Development Lifecycle</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/blog/2015/03/20/open-security-development-lifecycle/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2015 15:00:45 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/blog/2015/03/20/open-security-development-lifecycle/</guid>
      <description>We need a no-frills and roughly-right life-cycle to raise our level of software Security Assurance. Right now there are several security life-cycles both in the wild and available through vendors. None of those attend to the full spectrum of security and risk needs. Most are heavily centered around software testing but the security umbrella is much larger than that.&#xA;Maybe more importantly development and delivery methodologies have changed drastically over the last couple of years.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Control by Control</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/blog/2015/03/12/control-by-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2015 12:47:21 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/blog/2015/03/12/control-by-control/</guid>
      <description>You don&amp;rsquo;t read the glossary because no one reads that but how often do you jump straight to the end of a document to read an appendix?&#xA;Be truthful.&#xA;Well maybe you don&amp;rsquo;t but sometimes you really should.&#xA;Building the Tower Information Security controls have been a hot topic lately. Actually the discussion has been more around the lack of controls or how poorly the controls were implemented. In the InfoSec industry there are lots of definitions for these controls.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Security Capabilities</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/blog/2015/03/12/security-capabilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2015 12:45:30 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/blog/2015/03/12/security-capabilities/</guid>
      <description>Being Capable We talk a lot in security world. Most of the time we seem to talk about all the possibilities when we need to talk more about what we can actually do.&#xA;What are we capable of doing? We do we need to be capable of doing?&#xA;Being Capable with Capabilities When we want to talk with our partners, whether those partners are business-related, very technical or just your managers, you need some consistent way to describe what security does.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ecstatic Over Static Passwords</title>
      <link>//localhost:1313/blog/2015/03/12/ecstatic-over-static-passwords/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2015 12:43:10 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>//localhost:1313/blog/2015/03/12/ecstatic-over-static-passwords/</guid>
      <description>Well maybe not ecstatic but it is pretty exciting that I have been carrying around a way to house a strong static password and didn&amp;rsquo;t even realize it.&#xA;I have had a Yubikey for over a year now and have used it successfully with LastPass. A YubiKey is a handy USB or Near Field Communications (NFC) device that can generate a variety of authentication responses. The default is a One Time Password (OTP) that can be verified via a server running the Yubico software.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
