<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Secret Chipmunk Postings</title>
    <link>http://www.secretchipmunk.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Secret Chipmunk Postings</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 10:09:38 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.secretchipmunk.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the secret of the Grail?</title>
      <link>http://www.secretchipmunk.com/post/secretofthegrail/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 10:09:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.secretchipmunk.com/post/secretofthegrail/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.secretchipmunk.com/images/holygrail.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;Grail&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Grail Figure:&lt;/em&gt; What is the secret of the Grail? Who does it serve?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Perceval:&lt;/em&gt; You, my lord.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Grail Figure:&lt;/em&gt; Who am I?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Perceval:&lt;/em&gt; You are my lord and king. You are Arthur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Grail Figure:&lt;/em&gt; Have you found the secret that I have lost?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Perceval:&lt;/em&gt; Yes. You and the land are one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doesn&amp;rsquo;t this sound like a conversation you overheard between several architects standing around the watercooler?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you feel like we have long forgotten the secret of &lt;em&gt;The Architecture&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have our knights been roaming the countryside through famine and plague searching for the Holy Architecture to no avail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Where is Perceval!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;arthur:9b0652749ecb3aa7897d775c718b6839&#34;&gt;Arthur&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will not reiterate the whole saga of Arthur, his knights, the land, and the elusive Grail. There were many stories of Arthur but a powerful theme was that Arthur and the land were one. Arthur forgot that this was true. Being separated in spirit from the land around him he fell ill and the land fell into disarray. They could not be separated and the health of one depended on the other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After years of failed attempts to find the Grail and its secret Perceval had a vision of the long lost secret. Perceval met with Arthur and reunited the secret with the king. Arthur was restored and the land was restored along with him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;cue the music, blooming trees, and galloping horses&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-the-secret:9b0652749ecb3aa7897d775c718b6839&#34;&gt;What is the secret?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Secret of Architecture is that the Business and IT are one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or more importantly that you must architect the whole. This isn&amp;rsquo;t a new idea but as we begin to move faster and as we take on new aspects of being agile we can&amp;rsquo;t lose this secret. Let&amp;rsquo;s look at three areas that will help prevent the downfall of the kingdom.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Architecting is about optimization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Architecture must be intentional&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You must architect the whole&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;optimization:9b0652749ecb3aa7897d775c718b6839&#34;&gt;Optimization&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We recognize architecture because we believe that we can optimize the situation.  It takes skill, experience and cross area knowledge to understand how to realize these optimizations. That is the goal of architecting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;intentional:9b0652749ecb3aa7897d775c718b6839&#34;&gt;Intentional&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything has an architecture. The question is was it intentional?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without it being intentional you can&amp;rsquo;t expect much from architecting. You can&amp;rsquo;t expect a particular result. With Intentional Architecture you try to guide the overall outcome to align with what is most valued.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;whole:9b0652749ecb3aa7897d775c718b6839&#34;&gt;Whole&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter what you call yourself or what your area is there can be active architecture. You will have a scope and everything within that scope must be considered but not necessarily acted upon. This is the horizontal nature of architecting and is a primary difference between architecting and engineering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enterprise Architects look across the entire business (or they are supposed to anyway). Technical Architects should have a narrower scope and may not even be architecting at all. They may actually be just doing a really good job of engineering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trouble comes into play when we ignore items that fall within our scope. Setting a smaller scope is ok but do not make the scope large then leave areas to chance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;so-go-forth:9b0652749ecb3aa7897d775c718b6839&#34;&gt;So go forth!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do we expect that system optimization will happen when we only consider some of the parts?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You must architect the whole to have a better chance at obtaining the optimized results that you expect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The missing piece to all of this is the how. Do we implement tools and processes to crush the people into submission? Probably not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start with the fact that you are architecting the whole. Start with the fact that you can&amp;rsquo;t architect the business and leave out information technology or any other piece that makes up the business. This shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a secret but if we treat it like one we will never be successful as architects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For next time, let&amp;rsquo;s go figure out how to build agile and reactive architectures for everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;excalibur:9b0652749ecb3aa7897d775c718b6839&#34;&gt;Excalibur&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a side note if you have not seen &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.imdb.com/title/tt0082348/&#34;&gt;Excalibur&lt;/a&gt; please run out and find a copy to view right away. Inspiration is everywhere. You just need to look around.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenSDL Presentation</title>
      <link>http://www.secretchipmunk.com/post/opensdlpresentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Apr 2015 15:00:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.secretchipmunk.com/post/opensdlpresentation/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Here is the condensed version of how to mix security into agile development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.secretchipmunk.com/docs/AgileAndSecurityOilAndWaterHO.pdf&#34;&gt;Agile and Security. (PDF)&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;concept-platform:670ec0a62dda65178501a40f9a82b6d2&#34;&gt;Concept Platform&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A basic framework for the concept has been built around a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pmwiki.com&#34;&gt;Wiki&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opensamm.org&#34;&gt;OpenSAMM&lt;/a&gt;. This framework should be good enough to grow the idea and determine if it will add security value. The current version is here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opensdl.com&#34;&gt;Http://www.OpenSDL.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ronald Parker - Resume</title>
      <link>http://www.secretchipmunk.com/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2015 14:40:24 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.secretchipmunk.com/resume/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The important thing is that you always want to be smart and get things done while being nice to everyone around you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;summary:c59a67a3c7bc5faa453847420267045e&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am fortunate to be working with both information security and architecture. Both of these areas are horizontal enablers. When an awareness of architecture is combined with information security you have an opportunity to increase your overall level of security assurance. For the last several years I have delivered the mechanisms to support these ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;documents:c59a67a3c7bc5faa453847420267045e&#34;&gt;Documents&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.secretchipmunk.com/docs/RonaldParker_Resume_b.docx&#34;&gt;Resume - DOCX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.secretchipmunk.com/docs/RonaldParker_Resume_b.pdf&#34;&gt;Resume - PDF&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.secretchipmunk.com/docs/RonaldParker_Resume_t.txt&#34;&gt;Resume - TXT&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>B-Sides Nashville 2015</title>
      <link>http://www.secretchipmunk.com/post/BSidesNash2015/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Apr 2015 11:24:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.secretchipmunk.com/post/BSidesNash2015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I got the opportunity to be at B-Sides in Nashville over the weekend. It was a great opportunity to mingle and meet people who had an interest in information security. One of the best parts was a great mix of old professionals and quite a few new people who were interesting in seeing what security is all about. It was a good time and I appreciate all the effort it took to make it happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.irongeek.com&#34;&gt;Iron Geek&lt;/a&gt; made his services available so we have great recordings of all the talks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.irongeek.com/i.php?page=videos/bsidesnashville2015/mainlist&#34;&gt;B-Sides Nashvile Videos&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Making sure that security is woven throughout agile development can be a tricky task. This talk will walk through a solution to raising the overall level of security assurance in an agile development environment. The key goals for an environment are pretty straightforward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enable the developers with knowledge and processes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scale security with enabled people&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Assure a better level of security with enablement and scale&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a link to the lively video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.irongeek.com/i.php?page=videos/bsidesnashville2015/b04-agile-and-security-oil-and-water-ron-parker&#34;&gt;Agile and Security. Oil and Water?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An example of the metohd  and the general approach is at &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opensdl.com&#34;&gt;Open Security Development Lifecycle&lt;/a&gt;. Please take a look at this site and send in your comments and suggestions on how to make it easier for the general community to have a secure agile development environment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>agile</title>
      <link>http://www.secretchipmunk.com/topic/agile/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2015 15:18:55 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.secretchipmunk.com/topic/agile/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Security Development Lifecycle</title>
      <link>http://www.secretchipmunk.com/post/opensdl/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2015 15:00:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.secretchipmunk.com/post/opensdl/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;We need a no-frills and roughly-right life-cycle to raise our level of software Security Assurance. Right now there are several security life-cycles both in the wild and  available through vendors. None of those attend to the full spectrum of security and risk needs. Most are heavily centered around software testing but the security umbrella is much larger than that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe more importantly development and delivery methodologies have changed drastically over the last couple of years. This is even becoming true of the large scale enterprise shops. The pace of everything is increasing and the limited number of security practitioners can no longer scale to fit the need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We need a security development life-cycle that truly effects security assurance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;opensdl-objectives:6083725bddd4d0a914bec8a7bc730b76&#34;&gt;OpenSDL Objectives&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Make security an enabler for development teams&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Scale security to where it needs to be&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fit any development methodology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cover the major aspects of security&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Increase the overall level of security assurance&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;opensdl-deliverables:6083725bddd4d0a914bec8a7bc730b76&#34;&gt;OpenSDL Deliverables&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The essential security checklist&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An SDL knowledgebase driven by the community&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A platform that enables continuous improvement&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;concept-platform:6083725bddd4d0a914bec8a7bc730b76&#34;&gt;Concept Platform&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A basic framework for the concept has been built around a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pmwiki.com&#34;&gt;Wiki&lt;/a&gt; and the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opensamm.org&#34;&gt;OpenSAMM&lt;/a&gt;. This framework should be good enough to grow the idea and determine if it will add security value. The current version is here:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.opensdl.com&#34;&gt;Http://www.OpenSDL.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to be involved drop me a note at&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.twitter.com/scmunk&#34;&gt;@scmunk&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;or&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;mailto:scmunk@secretchipmunk.com&#34;&gt;scmunk@secretchipmunk.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Go Hugo?</title>
      <link>http://www.secretchipmunk.com/post/whyhugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2015 14:00:56 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.secretchipmunk.com/post/whyhugo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For years I have worked with WordPress along with its themes, plugins, and vulnerabilities. I even purchased a couple of themes. Yes, WP can make a pretty site but at the end of the day I spent a lot of time working on WP and not working on content. It was time to move on to a different way of publishing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were a several reasons that I moved from a dynamic site to a static site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple text-based content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Content that is easily managed/backed-up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Site that is free from distractions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minimal hosting requirements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Minimal upkeep&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After looking at least a half-a-dozen generators I went with &lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io/&#34; title=&#34;Hugo&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;. Hugo is a single executable written in Golang that has a rather flexible approach. It seems to be well supported and isn&amp;rsquo;t weighed down with all the problems mentioned above. You can either compile from source or copy a single executable to get started.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Golang looks interesting but luckily you don&amp;rsquo;t actually have to get into any Go at all unless you are designing a theme or working on the templates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Watch and see what happens. Hopefull there will be more content and less tweaking.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Architect</title>
      <link>http://www.secretchipmunk.com/post/whyarchitect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2015 15:09:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.secretchipmunk.com/post/whyarchitect/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ar chi tect: (v) design and make&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about landscaping your front yard. It is a lot more than just the sod or a couple of bushes. The overall look of your front yard comes from the color of your house, the looks of your house, the sidewalk, the driveway, the trees, and the shrubbery. It matters all the way down to how your grass has been mowed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you are going for a particular look you had better be thinking about these things a little bit up front and not just letting each and every service implement their part of the yard without some larger vision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You architect because you have a particular result in mind that can&amp;rsquo;t easily be achieved without coordination and thought across disciplines. You need a result that requires some systematic arrangement of ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;more-than-siloed-design:ebc611326388beea1ed63442849222e5&#34;&gt;More than siloed design&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.secretchipmunk.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/architectramp.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.secretchipmunk.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/11/architectramp.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;architectramp&#34; width=&#34;650&#34; height=&#34;432&#34; class=&#34;alignleft size-full wp-image-358&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Architecting is an every day problem and there are lots of situations that require more than a simple design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Building in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.universaldesignstyle.com/bad-design-style-case-26/&#34;&gt;accessibility&lt;/a&gt; without it seeming to be an add-on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Bringing about digital transformation and not just implementing a BYOD project&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Taking advantage of cloud-computing holistically and not just using it as an outsourcing opportunity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These situations need more than simple design. They need a design that is both deep and wide. This is also the key difference between architecting and engineering. An engineer might be the master of a single domain or even the master of a couple domains. They are the people to go to if you need specific answers around implementation or operations. Architects or the people with the role of an architect have to have a much wider exposure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The deep and wide role you actually need is often translated as being composed of both a technologist and a craftsman. The technologist is more academic while the craftsman has the real world experience. The useful and valuable architect has to balance these two based on the current need. Most tend to err on the side of the technologist which perpetuates the &lt;a href=&#34;http://agilemodeling.com/essays/enterpriseModelingAntiPatterns.htm#IvoryTowerArchitecture&#34;&gt;Ivory Tower&lt;/a&gt; problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The important situations we face are deep and wide when it comes to design. You may have a very complete understanding at a high level but the diagram you have drawn may not be implementable. It may be implementable but it may not exhibit the qualities that are required to be successful. The classic mistake is to look across a problem making lots conceptual decisions without real regard to the ramifications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being able to see the relationships and the ramifications in both the deep context and the wide context is good architecture. It is the reason to architect. It is the reason you need an architect.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Control by Control</title>
      <link>http://www.secretchipmunk.com/post/towercontrolbycontrol/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2015 12:47:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.secretchipmunk.com/post/towercontrolbycontrol/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;You don.t read the glossary because no one reads that but how often do you jump straight to the end of a document to read an appendix?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be truthful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well maybe you don.t but sometimes you really should.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;building-the-tower:d8e9488b145763e3df449f872c88aa21&#34;&gt;Building the Tower&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Information Security controls have been a hot topic lately. Actually the discussion has been more around the lack of controls or how poorly the controls were implemented. In the InfoSec industry there are lots of definitions for these controls. Many major governing, financial and auditing bodies have their own set of them or their own framework to explain them. In doing so they just about build their own security language.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This proliferation is also how we got to the infamous number of cross-references for controls we have in the security world. You have three pages of controls and then ten pages of cross-references where they explain why their controls are almost just the same but somehow they add extra value. The many sets of controls have become &lt;a href=&#34;http://bit.ly/1enYeyv&#34;&gt;The Tower of Babel&lt;/a&gt; for security professionals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-need-for-esperanto:d8e9488b145763e3df449f872c88aa21&#34;&gt;The Need for Esperanto&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe we don&amp;rsquo;t need &lt;a href=&#34;http://bit.ly/1fGwwAY&#34;&gt;Esperanto&lt;/a&gt; but we do need to look for more ways to use what we have and build upon it to make it better. We could be putting more energy into refactoring and improving than building new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No matter how much you like or dislike them the most stable set of control definitions is from NIST. To be more specific it is the &lt;a href=&#34;http://1.usa.gov/1hg5DEy&#34;&gt;NIST Special Publication 800-53 Rev 4&lt;/a&gt;. These controls are the most widely referenced controls for security today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the most interesting points about the 800-53 document is that all the good stuff is at the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.secretchipmunk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/80053Appd.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.secretchipmunk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/80053Appd.png&#34; alt=&#34;800-53 r4 Appendicies&#34; width=&#34;590&#34; height=&#34;213&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-221&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;F-1 is a full list or catalog of all the main security controls. These controls covered the main security goals of Confidentiality, Integrity and Availability (CIA). This was good for government agencies but it was missing an aspect for the commercial sector. The commercial sector is also worried about regulations and privacy issues. These are alluded to in the basic CIA triad but the triad does not provide the full coverage needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Revision 4 of the NIST 800-53 included a control catalog just for privacy issues. For many industries this is an important change. It now makes the 800-53 a lot more cross-industry capable and should eventually remove some of the need for so many different control frameworks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is the first half of what is included:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.secretchipmunk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/80053AppdJ.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.secretchipmunk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/11/80053AppdJ.png&#34; alt=&#34;80053AppdJ&#34; width=&#34;596&#34; height=&#34;360&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-222&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the addition of the privacy controls industries can now use this as a much broader reference than before. This is especially true if you are a regulated company.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-end:d8e9488b145763e3df449f872c88aa21&#34;&gt;The End&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Revisit the NIST offerings. It continues to be updated and be made more useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now we need to take a look at how this fits into the &lt;a href=&#34;http://1.usa.gov/18ERiNh&#34;&gt;CyberSecurity Framework update&lt;/a&gt; that was just released a couple of weeks ago. Maybe we can look at that next time.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security Capabilities</title>
      <link>http://www.secretchipmunk.com/post/securitycapabilitiesintro/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2015 12:45:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.secretchipmunk.com/post/securitycapabilitiesintro/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;being-capable:ac8ec186265b080c620f79c4a8c89888&#34;&gt;Being Capable&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We talk a lot in security world. Most of the time we seem to talk about all the possibilities when we need to talk more about what we can actually do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What are we capable of doing? We do we need to be capable of doing?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;being-capable-with-capabilities:ac8ec186265b080c620f79c4a8c89888&#34;&gt;Being Capable with Capabilities&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When we want to talk with our partners, whether those partners are business-related, very technical or just your managers, you need some consistent way to describe what security does. So many times we use a dozen terms that are all intermingled and ill-defined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One way to bring some consistency to your communications, to your planning and even to your budgeting process is to use a capabilities map. By defining what you do and using those definitions across the board you can eliminate one source of confusion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what is a capability?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TOGAF says that a &lt;a href=&#34;http://pubs.opengroup.org/architecture/togaf9-doc/arch/chap03.html&#34;&gt;capability&lt;/a&gt; is&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An ability that an organization, person, or system possesses. Capabilities are typically expressed in general and high-level terms and typically require a combination of organization, people, processes, and technology to achieve. For example, marketing, customer contact, or outbound telemarketing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the time capabilities are strictly business related but they can also be put in a different contexts. We can use them to describe what a security organization does or even what a functional area does within a larger organization. At its most basic level a capability is what you do but not how you do it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;an-example:ac8ec186265b080c620f79c4a8c89888&#34;&gt;An Example&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A security organization may put together a capabilities map in order to determine where it needs to invest in order to meet the challenges of the day or to help deliver secure business requirements. The same map can be used across all areas of the business. The leaders and stakeholders can all discuss security and risk using a consistent view.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is all a capabilities map really is. It is a view of the business or domain. If I bring up the &amp;lsquo;A&amp;rsquo; word, Architecture, for a moment I would say that capabilities are a first step in determining a conceptual view of your area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Start with a list of WHAT you provide:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating IDs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resetting passwords&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Managing access control&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configuration management&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After you make a first pass try to group similar capabilities. Once you have a several items try to group them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identity and Access Management

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Creating IDs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Resetting passwords&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Access control&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Network Security

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IDS/IPS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NAC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Configuration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Spend some time determining the minimum number of groups. Concentrate on building out the first two layers of your capabilities. We will call the top layer Level 1 Capabilities and the next layer down Level 2 Capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identity and Access Management&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manage Access Control&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manage Identity Lifecycle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide Infrastructure Security

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Provide Boundary Protection&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Manage Configuration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can make our list more presentable too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.secretchipmunk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/09/Capability.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.secretchipmunk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/09/Capability.png&#34; alt=&#34;Capability&#34; width=&#34;375&#34; height=&#34;284&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-188&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;recap:ac8ec186265b080c620f79c4a8c89888&#34;&gt;Recap&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what is a capability?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They are WHAT you do&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A capability may include people, processes and technologies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They are part of a terminology and &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Taxonomy&#34;&gt;taxonomy&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They can be represented with a picture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They can be represented with a list&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiple levels of capabilities can be used to represent varying levels of complexity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much more importantly what can we do once we have built a capabilities map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A map provides a common picture to be used in communicating&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The common terminology and views can help guide objectives and strategy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;They can be a common thread through your maturity models, gap analysis, and roadmaps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can easily see and communicate where you are investing your resources&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;next-time:ac8ec186265b080c620f79c4a8c89888&#34;&gt;Next Time&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Part II we will look to continue building out our example set of capabilities for a security organization. It would also be a good time to investigate why you can&amp;rsquo;t just reference all the other frameworks out there like ISO 27001, (ISC)2, or even SABSA.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ecstatic Over Static Passwords</title>
      <link>http://www.secretchipmunk.com/post/ecstaticpasswords/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2015 12:43:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.secretchipmunk.com/post/ecstaticpasswords/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Well maybe not ecstatic but it is pretty exciting that I have been carrying around a way to house a strong static password and didn&amp;rsquo;t even realize it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.secretchipmunk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/09/black_single.jpg&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.secretchipmunk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/09/black_single.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;YubiKey&#34; width=&#34;453&#34; height=&#34;400&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-182&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have had a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.yubico.com/&#34;&gt;Yubikey&lt;/a&gt; for over a year now and have used it successfully with &lt;a href=&#34;https://lastpass.com&#34;&gt;LastPass&lt;/a&gt;. A YubiKey is a handy USB or Near Field Communications (NFC) device that can generate a variety of authentication responses. The default is a One Time Password (OTP) that can be verified via a server running the Yubico software. It is an inexpensive way to provide a two-factor authentication method.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Little did I know, mainly because I don&amp;rsquo;t always read the instructions, that most YubiCo devices have the ability to hold multiple slots or multiple generators. A slot can be configured to generate the Yubico OTP, a Challenge-response, an industry standard OATH response or it can return a static password generated by you. You press the sensor quickly to activate slot 1 or you press it for more than two seconds to activate slot 2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-revelation:83feb0b7499959288b287011c714d110&#34;&gt;The Revelation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Totally missed the part about a static password.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Short static passwords are usually a bad thing but strong static passwords have their place. The best way to use this is to store a strong password suffix on the YubiKey and then you supply the prefix. What you end up with is a strong variable password that most people could not or would not take the time to memorize.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since the YubiKey allows you to store from 16-64 characters in the static section depending on the model the resulting password could be quite long. The key is configured using the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.yubico.com/products/services-software/personalization-tools/&#34;&gt;YubiCo Personalization Tool&lt;/a&gt; by selecting the &lt;em&gt;Static Password Option&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you use an 8 character prefix and a 32 character suffix that produces a 40 character password with ease. For example the prefix for your Twitter account may be &amp;lsquo;Blurb2Derp&amp;rsquo; and your static key may be &amp;lsquo;ljI10lakhjH_!@#947 *&amp;amp;ghdN1il1li1&amp;rsquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To use your new strong password type in your prefix then press the sensor for more than two seconds. A password wonder:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Blurb2DerpljI10lakhjH_!@#947 *&amp;amp;ghdN1il1li1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It still will be up to you to generate a total password that has the proper number of security bits and level of entropy. The good point is that you can store the static portion of a password that was generated randomly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using this method you could memorize a prefix for each site and use the YubiKey to enter the majority of the password. This would be great for those long &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.truecrypt.org/&#34; title=&#34;TruCrypt&#34;&gt;TruCrypt&lt;/a&gt; passwords that you never can seem to remember. This method may be an issue if you have some sites that disallow special characters or limit your password to 8 characters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ecstatic-static:83feb0b7499959288b287011c714d110&#34;&gt;Ecstatic Static&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are several different models of YubiKeys. YubiCo also provides several other authentication methods along with integrations with several major vendors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time to go change my passwords.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Architect from Hole in the Ground</title>
      <link>http://www.secretchipmunk.com/post/architectfromhole/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2015 12:41:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.secretchipmunk.com/post/architectfromhole/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Well maybe that is a little extreme but sometimes titles do seem to get twisted up especially in our title-laden world. My title &lt;em&gt;Security Architect&lt;/em&gt; has the word Architect in it but how closely related is that to an Enterprise Architect? Are we second-cousins three times removed or are we just not related at all?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-roles:b09c0a7d2de447e6b6bb3aacf838a00b&#34;&gt;The Roles&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It might make more sense to work through the main types of roles you might see on a daily basis. This list is by no means comprehensive but it does try to cover the ones that seem to deliver the most amount of confusion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;engineer:b09c0a7d2de447e6b6bb3aacf838a00b&#34;&gt;Engineer&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the security world these are the guys (girls, people) who traditionally have had their hands on the knobs and the switches. They are the ones who set the configurations, they write the rules, and they keep the machinery running. In recent times we have seen the security engineers expand their domain by including more than just firewall or IDS/IPS technologies. Their responsibilities are now including other areas such as the equivalent of information security data mining and data loss management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;architect:b09c0a7d2de447e6b6bb3aacf838a00b&#34;&gt;Architect&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where the confusion really sets in. An Architect is someone who looks for ways to deliver certain &lt;a href=&#34;http://bit.ly/175q0K9&#34;&gt;Quality Attributes&lt;/a&gt; for an environment. These attributes include things like performance, stability, security, flexibility, integrability, and many other &amp;ldquo;-ilities.&amp;rdquo; There are also different types of Architects so you may have more technical-oriented architects or more business-oriented architects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Security Architects are responsible for ensuring that the design of systems and environments meet security and compliance mandates. Depending on the specific flavor they may be working with the overall security strategy, establishing policies and standards, or they may be more specific and only deliver application security architecture.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;solution-architect:b09c0a7d2de447e6b6bb3aacf838a00b&#34;&gt;Solution Architect&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of the time you do not have specific Solution Architects in the security world. Solution Architects are usually more general in nature. They help to deliver the optimal answer by selecting the best standards, technologies, and systems that are available in the current environment. The key is that they don&amp;rsquo;t pick any new technologies or standards but they use what has already been selected for normal use in the enterprise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;enterprise-architect:b09c0a7d2de447e6b6bb3aacf838a00b&#34;&gt;Enterprise Architect&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enterprise Architects are all about optimizing the whole or the business with their primary partners being on the business side. They speak of delivering business value in the most effective way possible so when they present options they gauge them by Risk, Cost and Benefit. Their job is to help set business strategy and then give the best options for making those strategies become reality. In the end the are the trusted partners giving advice on how to move the business forward in the most efficient way possible. They are not the guys you will call in to &amp;ldquo;fix your computer.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-point:b09c0a7d2de447e6b6bb3aacf838a00b&#34;&gt;The Point&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The point to all of this division is that there are many different types of deliverables needed execute an optimized business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.secretchipmunk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/archRolesMatrix3.png&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.secretchipmunk.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/archRolesMatrix3.png&#34; alt=&#34;Roles Matrix&#34; width=&#34;622&#34; height=&#34;276&#34; class=&#34;alignnone size-full wp-image-154&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every role has a part to play or a piece to contribute. Architects keep Engineers out of business meetings. Engineers somehow still manage to keep things running in spite bad architecture decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most import action for you is to determine your role and make sure you are spending the time necessary to be the best you can be in that role. I would suggest &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sans.org/&#34;&gt;SANS&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.isc2.org/&#34;&gt;(ISC)2&lt;/a&gt; for ways to improve your security stature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What have you been called lately?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Storytelling</title>
      <link>http://www.secretchipmunk.com/post/storytelling/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2015 12:38:25 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.secretchipmunk.com/post/storytelling/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Data breaches cost over $150 per record. An identity is stolen every 3 seconds. DDoS attacks are up over 43% this year alone. Some random statement on how poor most passwords are these days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does this droning sound like what is driving your security program? Even though these facts are true they may not win the hearts and minds of your security decision makers. Everyone seems to have these facts these days so in a way they are becoming background noise. This can make your job of selling the correct security solution for your business much harder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is a security professional to do when the facts, data and logic don&amp;rsquo;t sway the masses to action?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;storytelling:e4e93fe896522e04f5d5ddab88543da6&#34;&gt;Storytelling&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer is simple. You need to engage your decision makers with a story that conveys the issues, reveals the villains and describes best solution for the business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From our friends at Wikipedia &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Storytelling&#34; title=&#34;Storytelling&#34;&gt;Storytelling&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;is the conveying of events in words, and images, often by improvisation or embellishment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story builds a relationship between the cold facts and the real-life context that the decision maker understands. You can embed the facts in the story but they need to be backed up with those embellishments that add relevancy. This doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean you should lie, it just says you should add meaning to the facts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Engage your audience by building a story that conveys what matters to them. Give them a reason to care about your facts. Realize that that in order to activate the facts you have to attach some emotion to them otherwise they are just cold, hard facts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;next-steps:e4e93fe896522e04f5d5ddab88543da6&#34;&gt;Next Steps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pick a small number of facts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Know how your audience is affected by these facts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Most importantly know how your customer base is affected&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build a story around the root cause of these issues&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Introduce a solution&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Quickly mention next steps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use images over any verbiage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have lots of supporting information, charts and graphs push them to the end of the presentation. Only pull them out if someone asks a direct question regarding those facts. Use the story to get agreement. Use the facts later on once you start really working through next steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are lots of story resources out there on the web and I encourage you to utilize those.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://lifehacker.com/5965703/the-science-of-storytelling-why-telling-a-story-is-the-most-powerful-way-to-activate-our-brains&#34; title=&#34;LifeHacker&#34;&gt;LifeHacker&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ted.com/playlists/62/how_to_tell_a_story.html&#34; title=&#34;TED&#34;&gt;TED&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://weblog.tetradian.com/2011/08/07/ea-is-all-about-story/&#34; title=&#34;Architecture Storytelling&#34;&gt;Enterprise Architecture&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion:e4e93fe896522e04f5d5ddab88543da6&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may not be able to employee this tactic for each engagement but it might be worth putting the extra storytelling effort in on the important solutions you are trying to sell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a side note this is why so many PowerPoint presentations that were based solely on facts have caused widespread head trauma over the years.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Order of Things</title>
      <link>http://www.secretchipmunk.com/post/orderofthings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2015 12:21:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.secretchipmunk.com/post/orderofthings/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;sequence-diagrams:c0cb276dc2df1786ccc4a48d54acf821&#34;&gt;Sequence Diagrams&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am not a huge fan of traditional UML diagrams for long term documentation. Most diagrams are quickly rendered old and useless. There are times though when you need to convey the sequence of operations between several entities. It is hard to beat the Sequence Diagram for those situations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are plenty of tools that let you build some very sophisticated Sequence Diagrams. I try to avoid spending more time building a Sequence Diagram than it would take to write the code behind the diagram. Luckily there is a good alternative that is almost as good as the back of a napkin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Web Sequence Diagrams allows you to enter some simple text and it produces a variety of diagram styles. It diagrams as you type plus it has a menu of examples that you can easily insert into your text. Here is a small example of how SAML should work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;title Simple SAML

Browser-&amp;gt;Resource: Resource Request
Resource-&amp;gt;Browser: Redirect
Browser-&amp;gt;STS: 
STS-&amp;gt;STS: Cook up assertions
STS-&amp;gt;Browser: Assertions
Browser-&amp;gt;Resource: Assertions
Resource-&amp;gt;Resource: Authorize with Assertions
Resource-&amp;gt;Browser: Return Resource
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which produces this diagram:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.secretchipmunk.com/images/simplesaml.png&#34; alt=&#34;Simple SAML&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So if you need a quick Sequence Diagram try &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.websequencediagrams.com/&#34;&gt;Web Sequence Diagrams&lt;/a&gt;. You can copy the above example and paste it into the diagram editor to see how easy it is to use.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Architecture</title>
      <link>http://www.secretchipmunk.com/topic/architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2015 14:00:22 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.secretchipmunk.com/topic/architecture/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Architecture is here.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>