<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Architecture on Secret Chipmunk</title>
    <link>/tags/architecture/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Architecture on Secret Chipmunk</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>(c) 2021 Ron Parker</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/architecture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AWS Solution Architect Professional (SAP)</title>
      <link>/blog/2020/12/30/aws-solution-architect-professional-sap/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2020/12/30/aws-solution-architect-professional-sap/</guid>
      <description>On Flying Time It has been a busy year. A lot of time was spent actually working with AWS and a good many of their offerings. So much time that the whole year flew by and I almost didn&amp;rsquo;t have the time to take the certification I had been working on for so long.
Another issue was that test centers were still not open in my area so the testing had to be proctored.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AWS Certification</title>
      <link>/blog/2019/06/18/aws-certification/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019/06/18/aws-certification/</guid>
      <description>Certification Path Amazon has several paths for certification that target different job roles. Having an architecture and a security background I decided to move towards the full AWS Solution Architect first then pursue a security specialty later on if it seemed valuable. The first place to start is an overview for the learning paths
After looking at the prerequisites my certification path looks like this:
 Cloud Practitioner -&amp;gt; Solution Architect-Associate -&amp;gt; Solution architecture</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling Information Security</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/09/05/modeling-information-security/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2018 12:45:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/09/05/modeling-information-security/</guid>
      <description>There is a new menu option dedicated to modeling called Models.
The current model is in the Archi format and is easily downloadable. It covers all the capabilities we have discussed up to this point. As we move forward we will add more to this model and build out other artifacts that support our architecture vision. We may even get adventurous and include a PowerPoint or two.
Up Next More architecture of course!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Security Capabilities All The Way Down</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/08/23/security-capabilities-all-the-way-down/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 12:45:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/08/23/security-capabilities-all-the-way-down/</guid>
      <description>All the Way Down We continue our series on using capabilities to our advantage in creating design and architecture. We will cover how we can model information security all the way down. This section, like the section on Cloud Capabilities, begins with the layout of those abilities.
We also have to remember that capabilities are the highest level or the highest description we will be using. The actual behaviors and implementations will be much more detailed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quality Wardley Maps</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/08/18/quality-wardley-maps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 12:45:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/08/18/quality-wardley-maps/</guid>
      <description>Mapping If you are not familiar with Simon Wardley and his world of mapping you need to first jump over to his blog-book on mapping. It is a detailed set of pages that are well worth your time to read through and practice.
Quality Attributes Quality Attributes (QAs) are those non-functional traits that we try to describe and require when designing processes, systems, and software. They describe a quality of the thing in question.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foundations for Cloud Capabilities - Continued</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/08/12/foundations-for-cloud-capabilities-continued/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2018 12:45:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/08/12/foundations-for-cloud-capabilities-continued/</guid>
      <description>If you missed it, read the first post on Foundations for Cloud Capabilities. We will be building on that as we expand our design.
Foundational Areas We covered these foundational areas in the first post. We will finish out our list so we can begin looking at architecture mapping processes.
 Governance Environments Request and Provisioning Backup and Recovery Disaster Recovery Cost Management  We will finish the descriptions for the rest of the list.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foundations for Cloud Capabilities</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/07/24/foundations-for-cloud-capabilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jul 2018 12:45:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/07/24/foundations-for-cloud-capabilities/</guid>
      <description>A Survey If you missed it, read the post on Cloud Capabilities first. We will be building on that as we expand our design.
This is a pretty long and involved topic so will be broken into a couple of posts. The first post or two will describe all the foundational elements that may be needed. Then we will move into more architectural direction and artifacts to use in the process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Capabilities</title>
      <link>/blog/2018/07/22/cloud-capabilities/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2018 12:45:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018/07/22/cloud-capabilities/</guid>
      <description>Cloud Service Provider Capabilities What do we have the ability to do? Or even better, what do we want to be able to do?
It sounds like an easy question and it is asked all the time for all domains. As we do any type of design it always helps to have definitions and groupings of your abilities. This allows you to compare, explain changes, and explain gaps in a consistent manner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ready, Set, Architect!</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/07/20/ready-set-architect/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 15:18:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/07/20/ready-set-architect/</guid>
      <description>A Quick Talk This is a quick tour through why we need to architect, a couple of the frameworks, and finally several helpful tools.
It started out as a 5-minute lightning talk but turn more into an 8-minute flashflood. I want to thank the @chadevs for giving me the time to come and speak to the great group there. There was a good crowd that filled up the room. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t attended a Chattanooga Developers, ChaDevs, Lunch Meeting then check them out on Meetup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Session Box</title>
      <link>/blog/2017/05/01/session-box/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 May 2017 20:07:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2017/05/01/session-box/</guid>
      <description>I draw a lot of diagrams. With all these diagrams there are an endless number of revisions and refinements created in the process. Some of the changes are necessary while others are definitely not earth-shattering.
Timeboxing  In time management, timeboxing allocates a fixed time period, called a time box, to each planned activity. It is also used for individual use to address personal tasks in a smaller time frame.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Entitlements in a Multi-tenant World</title>
      <link>/blog/2016/09/18/entitlements-in-a-multi-tenant-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Sep 2016 12:21:29 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2016/09/18/entitlements-in-a-multi-tenant-world/</guid>
      <description>We are in a super-shared, and super-scaled world where rights are no longer concentrated in one place. Your rights and permissions are living everywhere in the neighborhood. They have left home.
These is the presentation I used for a basic talk on why it is important to understnad how entitlements work these day. It was meant for presenting but you may get somehting out of it.
 Entitlements in a Multi-tenant World(PDF) Entitlements in a Multi-tenant World(PPTx)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is the secret of the Grail?</title>
      <link>/blog/2015/05/12/what-is-the-secret-of-the-grail/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 May 2015 10:09:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015/05/12/what-is-the-secret-of-the-grail/</guid>
      <description>Grail Figure: What is the secret of the Grail? Who does it serve?
Perceval: You, my lord.
Grail Figure: Who am I?
Perceval: You are my lord and king. You are Arthur.
Grail Figure: Have you found the secret that I have lost?
Perceval: Yes. You and the land are one.
 Doesn&amp;rsquo;t this sound like a conversation you overheard between several architects standing around the watercooler?
Do you feel like we have long forgotten the secret of The Architecture?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Architect</title>
      <link>/blog/2015/03/16/why-architect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2015 15:09:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015/03/16/why-architect/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ar chi tect: (v) design and make&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Think about landscaping your front yard. It is a lot more than just the sod or a couple of bushes. The overall look of your front yard comes from the color of your house, the looks of your house, the sidewalk, the driveway, the trees, and the shrubbery. It matters all the way down to how your grass has been mowed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Architect from Hole in the Ground</title>
      <link>/blog/2015/03/12/architect-from-hole-in-the-ground/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2015 12:41:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2015/03/12/architect-from-hole-in-the-ground/</guid>
      <description>Well maybe that is a little extreme but sometimes titles do seem to get twisted up especially in our title-laden world. My title Security Architect has the word Architect in it but how closely related is that to an Enterprise Architect? Are we second-cousins three times removed or are we just not related at all?
The Roles It might make more sense to work through the main types of roles you might see on a daily basis.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
